



 

   //Questions array

   let questions = [

    {

         number:1,

         question: "Who defined tragedy as an imitation of an action that is serious",

         answer : "Aristotle",

         options : [

                          "William Wordsworth",

                          "Aristotle",

                          "Blake Shelton",

                          "Pythagoras"

                        ]

    

    },

    {

         number:2,

         question: "The tragic heroes hamartia or defects should be the outcome of",

         answer : "Error in judgement",

         options : [

                          "Conflict",

                          "Error in judgement",

                          "Personal development issues",

                          "Bad character"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:3,

         question: "Tragic flaw in Greek is called",

         answer : "Hubris",

         options : [

                          "Hubris",

                          "Hamartia",

                          "Haiku",

                          "Dran"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:4,

         question: "___ is achieved through feelings of sorrow and terror",

         answer : "Tragic catharsis",

         options : [

                          "Tragic fall",

                          "Tragic catharsis",

                          "Conflict",

                          "Denouement"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:5,

         question: "___ is a weapon used to expose ignorance and deception",

         answer : "Humor",

         options : [

                          "Humor",

                          "Plot",

                          "Situational irony",

                          "Comic catharsis"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:6,

         question: "The primary character of a melodrama is",

         answer : "Villain",

         options : [

                          "Hero",

                          "Protagonist",

                          "Villain",

                          "Heroine"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:7,

         question: "The main goal of melodrama is to",

         answer : "Entertain",

         options : [

                          "Amuse",

                          "Criticize",

                          "Elicit emotions",

                          "Entertain"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:8,

         question: "Aristotle claimed that the plot is __",

         answer : "Life and soul of tragedy",

         options : [

                          "A tool for tragic catharsis",

                          "Life and soul of tragedy",

                          "Entire storyline of a play",

                          "Basic structure of drama"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:9,

         question: "The two key elements of an enjoyable story line is",

         answer : "Suspense and surprise",

         options : [

                          "Suspense and surprise",

                          "Plot and setting",

                          "Character and action",

                          "Comedy and tragedy"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:10,

         question: "___ is a technique used in exposition part of a plot, when the writer uses subtle indications to get the audience ready for upcoming events",

         answer : "Foreshadowing",

         options : [

                          "Foreshadowing",

                          "Soliloquy",

                          "Catharsis",

                          "Flashback"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:11,

         question: "In tragedy, denouement is often called the ___",

         answer : "Catastrophe",

         options : [

                          "Catastrophe",

                          "Falling action",

                          "Resolution",

                          "End point"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:12,

         question: "A well-known character is called",

         answer : "Round character",

         options : [

                          "Round character",

                          "Flat character",

                          "Static character",

                          "Dynamic character"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:13,

         question: "A character that lacks depth and is usually one-dimensional is called",

         answer : "Flat character",

         options : [

                          "Flat character",

                          "Round character",

                          "Static character",

                          "Dynamic character"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:14,

         question: "The character that goes through changes in a story is called",

         answer : "Dynamic character",

         options : [

                          "Round character",

                          "Flat character",

                          "Dynamic character",

                          "Static character"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:15,

         question: "__ character serve as contrast by refusing to change throughout the entire story",

         answer : "Static character",

         options : [

                          "Dynamic character",

                          "Static character",

                          "Flat character",

                          "Round character"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:16,

         question: "Which of these is a component of the dramatic character's personality",

         answer : "Thought",

         options : [

                          "Soliloquy",

                          "Catharsis",

                          "Thought",

                          "Dialogue"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:17,

         question: "All of a play's visual components fall under __ category",

         answer : "Spectacle",

         options : [

                          "Props",

                          "Spectacle",

                          "Stageries",

                          "Prompts"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:18,

         question: "A drama condensed into a single episode delivered to a person or group in a one-sided interaction is known as",

         answer : "Monologue",

         options : [

                          "Interlude",

                          "Prologue",

                          "Aside",

                          "Monologue"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:19,

         question: "The line of dialogue delivered by a character to the playâ€™s audience is known as",

         answer : "Aside",

         options : [

                          "Monologue",

                          "Aside",

                          "Interlude",

                          "Soliloquy"  

                          ]

    

    },

    {

         number:20,

         question: "The goal of literary appreciation is __",

         answer : "To increase the value of written works",

         options : [

                          "To increase the value of written works",

                          "To prescribe methods of literary writing",

                          "To organise written works",

                          "To analyse written works"  

                          ]

    

    }

     ];   